# Furkan Borak

Plano, TX

-Email me on Indeed: http://www.indeed.com/r/Furkan-Borak/a01ecb6a7ae0293a

Recent MS in Computer Science & IT graduate with 2+ years of RF engineering experience. In search of a challenging and growth-oriented full-time position in RF/Network Engineering that will leverage my technical and professional expertise.

### Work Experience

### **RF Design Engineer**

Amdocs - Frisco, TX July 2019 to Present

- Create RFDS for real estate & construction purpose with the designed equipment and frequency bands (mainly with AWS,PCS,700, 850, 5G, CBRS) and 4G/5G CIQs for Verizon.
- · Work with the real estate, construction, and integration teams to troubleshoot any design related queries.
- Efficiently deliver various milestones of small cell and macro projects by ensuring Service Level Agreements for Verizon Carolina, Tennessee, Baltimore and Washington markets.
- Contribute to RF design of regional cellular network by using Atoll to perform coverage analysis.
- Test VOLTE and Data Wireless Network by using DMAT, XCAL, and TEMS Investigation.
- · Establish design criteria, link budget and traffic analysis as needed for network design.
- Identify the most suitable location for a small cell node by running propagation plots using Atoll
- · Analyze KPIs pulled from TRUECALL, Google Earth, ELPT to efficiently design small cells producing accurate coverage predictions and offload analysis for LTE bands using Atoll.
- Responsible for proper documentation of regulatory filing, EME compliance and 911 submissions.

#### **Electronics Engineering Intern**

Turkish Radio and Television Corporation - Ankara, TR June 2013 to September 2013

- Implemented telecommunication systems for a variety of corporate users.
- Applied standard engineering techniques and procedures.

#### **Electrical Engineering Intern**

Ankara Railway Maintenance and Repair Services - Ankara, TR June 2012 to September 2012

- Maintenance of contactors, train fans, and controller motherboard repairs.
- Quality control and quality assessment of engines.

#### Education

### M.S. in Computer Science & Information Technologies

Texas A & M University-Commerce - Commerce, TX

August 2017 to May 2021

# **B.S. in Electrical & Electronics Engineering**

Erciyes University - Kayseri

September 2010 to September 2014

## Skills

- Microsoft & Linux tools
- Proteus (ISIS)
- Solid Works Programming Skills: C
- C++
- Assembly
- Python
- R Language Telecom Tools: IMNOS
- RFDS
- ATOLL
- ASSET
- True Call
- Element
- ActixOne
- Citrix
- Ericsson tools
- DMAT
- TEMS
- XCAL Certificate Cisco CCNA English Turkish
- 4G/LTE
- Network Engineering

# Certifications and Licenses

### **CCNA**